Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/felixsievers (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Public Relations Start-ups Marketing

Languages

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual) Französisch (Elementary) Englisch (Full Professional)

Honors-Awards
30u30 (PR Report Awards)

Felix Sievers

Strategist and communicator at heart + music, MTG, NBA, and comic book nerd. CEO @ FUTUR III.

Hannover

Zusammenfassung

Strategist and communicator at heart + music, MTG, NBA, and comic book addict. Co-Founder and CEO @ FUTUR III.

Believes in five core requirements for great work: awesome people, challenging tasks, freedom to experiment, ruthless pragmatism, and brilliant cognition.

Strong entrepreneurial and communications background acquired by working as an Associate @ Earlybird Venture Capital, a strategic consultant for communications and digital transformation @ Hering Schuppener and RCKT. In addition, gathered entrepreneurial experience by supporting the IPO of Rocket Internet, working on the social tv start-up title, and acting as Head of Communications for the mobile security start-up mediaTest digital. He was part of the young professional award "30u30" (PR Report), is a mentor in the accelerator program of Hafven and guest lecturer for Media Entrepreneurship @ University of Music, Drama and Media Hanover (dept. IJK).

My approach to work is fueled by the curiosity to learn something new every day, meet inspiring people, and do my absolute best.

Berufserfahrung

FUTUR DREI
Co-Founder & CEO
Juli 2018 - Present (3 Jahre 9 Monate)
Hannover und Umgebung, Deutschland

The strategic creative consultancy supports organizations – from startups to major corporations – in the areas of PR, design, branding and social media.

Institut für Journalistik und Kommunikationsforschung Hannover Guest Lecturer and Coach, Media Entrepreneurship April 2019 - Present (3 Jahre) Hannover und Umgebung, Deutschland

Department of Journalism and Communication Research (IJK), Hanover; University of Music, Drama and Media: Media Entrepreneurship is an interactive and experiential start-up simulation focused on the process of taking a media venture from concept to practical execution. http://www.mediaentrepreneurship.de/

Hafven
Mentor
Juli 2018 - Present (3 Jahre 9 Monate)
Hannover und Umgebung, Deutschland

Hafven is one of the largest innovation communities in Germany. Mentor at the independent accelerator – for all startups that put people at the heart of smart solutions.

Earlybird Venture Capital Associate and External Consultant März 2017 - Present (5 Jahre 1 Monat) Berlin Area, Germany

Earlybird is a venture capital investor focused on European technology companies. Founded in 1997, Earlybird invests in all growth and development phases of a company.

With EUR 1.5 billion under management, seven IPOs and 30 trade sales, Earlybird is one of the most successful venture capital firms in Europe. Beyond delivering financial returns, we clearly see our own entrepreneurial responsibility for the environment as well as society and strive to make a positive contribution towards solving the global climate crisis.

HERING SCHUPPENER Analyst and Client Executive Oktober 2015 - Mai 2017 (1 Jahr 8 Monate) Berlin

HERING SCHUPPENER is the leading strategic communications advisor in Germany. We advise local and international groups, large mid-market firms, financial investors, associations and institutions in mission-critical situations and on an on-going basis.

HERING SCHUPPENER DIGITAL advises exceptional startups and established corporate players on their journey in the digital age.

RCKT. Rocket Communications Communication Manager Mai 2015 - Oktober 2015 (6 Monate)

RCKT is a full-service agency that stands for digital change.

mediaTest digital Head of Communications 2012 - April 2015 (3 Jahre)

Hannover

mediaTest digital is the European market leader for mobile security solutions with regard to Enterprise Mobility and Mobile Application Management. Founded in 2012, the Hanover-based company is today securing mobile devices for business clients like Lufthansa or Deutsche Bahn on a worldwide scale.

Rocket Internet AG
PR & Communications
August 2014 - Oktober 2014 (3 Monate)
Berlin und Umgebung, Deutschland

Internship at the leading global internet platform outside the US & China.

Member of Rocket's Corporate Communications team that lead all communications activities during the Initial Public Offering (IPO) at the Frankfurt Stock Exchange.

trioscore GmbH Junior PR Manager März 2012 - September 2012 (7 Monate) Hannover

Internship at

mediaTest digital
Players Rock Entertainment
browserspiele.de

Legrand & Rosenboom Social Media & other Projects Dezember 2011 - Januar 2012 (2 Monate) Hamburg

Internship

Agency for brand communication

Projects for Le Crobag, Schiffl & Partner, Sport 56 & Cawila, Cbb-Software

Verlagsgesellschaft Madsack GmbH & Co.KG Media Beratung; Vertriebsmarketing & Werbung Juli 2011 - November 2011 (5 Monate) Hannover

Internship

The MADSACK Media Group originates from the year 1893, when the publisher August Madsack founded the Hannoverscher Anzeiger in Hannover. From this, the Media Group developed into one of the largest publishing companies in Germany.

Ausbildung

Hochschule für Musik, Theater und Medien Hannover Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Department of Journalism and Communication Research (IJK), Medienmanagement · (2012 - 2016)